Hugo Bedau Papers MS027
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
Hugo Bedau Papers
1949 -- 2001
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
Bedau, Hugo Adam
MS027
10.8 Linear Feet
Arrangement
This collection is organized into three series: Correspondence; Subject Files; and Writings and Publications.
Scope and Contents
The bulk of this collection is composed of professional correspondence and publications as well as subject files relating to professional conferences and teaching engagements.
Related Materials
UA150, Center for the Study of Decision Making, DCA
Biographical / Historical
Hugo Adam Bedau (1927-2012) was a long time faculty member and chair of the Department of Philosophy and Austin B. Fletcher Professor of Philosophy. He received his undergraduate education at the naval training program at University of South Carolina and at the University of Redlands, where he graduated in 1949. He completed his master's at Boston University (1951) and his PhD (1961) at Harvard. Prior to coming to Tufts, Bedau taught at Dartmouth, Princeton, and Reed, as well as serving as an adjunct or visiting lecturer at several colleges. In 1966 he joined the Tufts faculty where his refusal to take a Loyalty Oath required by the state of Massachusetts nearly ended his Tufts career before it began. However, a court injunction and subsequent vindication by the Massachusetts Supreme Court solidified his place among the faculty for many years to come.
Bedau was one of the co- founders of the National Coalition to Abolish the Death Penalty and he continued to be active in the organization in different positions. He became a member of the American Civil Liberties Union in the 1950s and testified against the death penalty before the U.S. Congress and state legislatures. Bedau wrote and published extensively on the subject of capital punishment, the death penalty, and critical thinking in the scholarly literature as well as in newspapers. He edited or co-edited volumes on social, political, moral and legal philosophy (The Death Penalty in America, Capital Punishment in the United States and Debating the Death Penalty). His books include The Courts, the Constitution, and Capital Punishment (1977), Death is Different (1987), and Killing as Punishment (2004). The majority of Bedau's research and papers on these subjects are located at the M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections at the State University of New York, Albany.
In addition to writing and teaching at Tufts, Bedau was a frequent guest lecturer and conference participant. He was consistently rated as a favorite teacher by his Tufts students both at home and abroad. He was elected Romanell - Phi Beta Kappa Professor of Philosophy in 1994 and his Romanell lecture was published in 1997 as Making Moral Choices. He received the August Vollmer Award from the American Society of Criminology as well as the Roger Baldwin Award from the ACLU of Massachusetts in 2003.
Bedau retired in 1999. In September 2006, in celebration of his 80th birthday, the Department of Philosophy established the Hugo Adam Bedau Fund for Civil Liberties. Although retired, Bedau continued to research and publish along with his wife, Constance Putnam. He died August 13, 2012, survived by his wife and four children from a previous marriage: Mark, Paul, Guy and Lauren Bedau Evans.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for research.
Bedau, Hugo Adam; Philosophers -- United States -- Archives.; Alumni collections
- Correspondence, 1955 -- 1999; MS027.001; 2.4 Linear Feet
  Scope and Contents
  This series consists of correspondence received by Hugo Bedau, as well as copies of correspondence he created.
  Arrangement
  This series is arranged chronologically.
  Conditions Governing Access
  Open for research.
  - General Correspondence (1 of 2), 1955 -- 1968; MS027.001.001.00001 (Box 1)
  - General Correspondence (2 of 2), 1955 -- 1968; MS027.001.001.00002 (Box 1)
  - General Correspondence, 1966 -- 1969; MS027.001.001.00003 (Box 1)
  - General Correspondence, 1970; MS027.001.001.00004 (Box 1)
  - General Correspondence, 1971; MS027.001.001.00005 (Box 1)
  - General Correspondence, 1972; MS027.001.001.00006 (Box 1)
  - General Correspondence, 1973; MS027.001.001.00007 (Box 1)
  - Unfiled, 1973; MS027.001.001.00008 (Box 1)
  - General Correspondence, 1974; MS027.001.001.00009 (Box 1)
  - Unfiled, 1974; MS027.001.001.00010 (Box 1)
  - General Correspondence, 1975; MS027.001.001.00011 (Box 1)
  - Unfiled, 1975; MS027.001.001.00012 (Box 1)
  - General Correspondence, 1976; MS027.001.001.00013 (Box 1)
  - Unfiled, 1976; MS027.001.001.00014 (Box 1)
  - 1977, MS027.001.001.00015 (Box 1)
  - Unfiled, 1977; MS027.001.001.00016 (Box 1)
  - 1978, MS027.001.001.00017 (Box 1)
  - Unfiled, 1978; MS027.001.001.00018 (Box 1)
  - 1979, MS027.001.001.00019 (Box 1)
  - Unfiled, 1979; MS027.001.001.00020 (Box 1)
  - 1980, MS027.001.001.00021 (Box 1)
  - Unfiled, 1980; MS027.001.001.00022 (Box 1)
  - 1981, MS027.001.001.00023 (Box 1)
  - 1981, MS027.001.001.00024 (Box 1)
  - 1982, MS027.001.002.00001 (Box 2)
  - 1982, MS027.001.002.00002 (Box 2)
  - 1983, MS027.001.002.00003 (Box 2)
  - 1983, MS027.001.002.00004 (Box 2)
  - 1984, MS027.001.002.00005 (Box 2)
  - 1984, MS027.001.002.00006 (Box 2)
  - 1985, MS027.001.002.00007 (Box 2)
  - 1985, MS027.001.002.00008 (Box 2)
  - General Correspondence, 1986; MS027.001.002.00009 (Box 2)
  - 1986, MS027.001.002.00010 (Box 2)
  - General Correspondence, 1987; MS027.001.002.00011 (Box 2)
  - 1987, MS027.001.002.00012 (Box 2)
  - 1988, MS027.001.002.00013 (Box 2)
  - 1989, MS027.001.002.00014 (Box 2)
  - 1990, MS027.001.002.00015 (Box 2)
  - 1991, MS027.001.002.00016 (Box 2)
  - 1992, MS027.001.002.00017 (Box 2)
  - 1993, MS027.001.002.00018 (Box 2)
  - 1994, MS027.001.002.00019 (Box 2)
  - 1995, MS027.001.002.00020 (Box 2)
  - 1996, MS027.001.002.00021 (Box 2)
  - 1997, MS027.001.002.00022 (Box 2)
  - 1998, MS027.001.002.00023 (Box 2)
  - Correspondence, 1999; MS027.001.002.00024 (Box 2)
  - General Corrrespondence from Discussion Folders, 1982 -- 1999; MS027.001.002.00025 (Box 2)
- Subject Files, 1953 -- 1999; MS027.002; 3.6 Linear Feet
  This series contains Bedau's subject files regarding teaching engagements, conferences, and his work with various professional and non-profit organizations.
  This series is arranged alphabetically.
  - 1996 Wittgenstein Conference, MS027.002.003.00001 (Box 3)
  - Academic Freedom (1 of 3), 1974 -- 1987; MS027.002.003.00002 (Box 3)
  - Academic Freedom (2 of 3), 1971 -- 1972; MS027.002.003.00003 (Box 3)
  - Academic Freedom (3 of 3), 1970 -- 1972; MS027.002.003.00004 (Box 3)
  - Amsterdam, 1993; MS027.002.003.00005 (Box 3)
  - Ann Arbor Trip, 1977; MS027.002.003.00006 (Box 3)
  - APA April '76 - Gibbard, 1976; MS027.002.003.00007 (Box 3)
  - APA Meeting, 1966; MS027.002.003.00008 (Box 3)
  - APA Meeting (Pac. Div.), 1971; MS027.002.003.00009 (Box 3)
  - APA Phil of Law Comm., 1975 -- 1990; MS027.002.003.00010 (Box 3)
  - APA of L Newsletter, 1977 -- 1992; MS027.002.003.00011 (Box 3)
  - APA Programs, 1953 -- 1989; MS027.002.003.00012 (Box 3)
  - APA Symposium on Retribution, 1978; MS027.002.003.00013 (Box 3)
  - ASC Paper, 1991; MS027.002.003.00014 (Box 3)
  - A.S.P. and L. P., 1961 -- 1998; MS027.002.003.00015 (Box 3)
  - ASPL Program, 1971; MS027.002.003.00016 (Box 3)
  - ASPLP Prog, 1983; MS027.002.003.00017 (Box 3)
  - A.U. Conference, 1984; MS027.002.003.00018 (Box 3)
  - Austria, 1988; MS027.002.003.00019 (Box 3)
  - Bentham 250, 1998; MS027.002.003.00020 (Box 3)
  - Bentham Society, 1992 -- 1999; MS027.002.003.00021 (Box 3)
  - Brandeis Evaluation, 1985; MS027.002.003.00022 (Box 3)
  - Brockport, 1996; MS027.002.003.00023 (Box 3)
  - Buffalo Conference, 1987 -- 1995; MS027.002.003.00024 (Box 3)
  - Cambridge, 1988; MS027.002.003.00025 (Box 3)
  - Cntr for Study of H.R., 1981 -- 1998; MS027.002.003.00026 (Box 3)
  - Clare Hall / I of C, 1978 -- 1979; MS027.002.003.00027 (Box 3)
  - Colby College Eval., 1983; MS027.002.003.00028 (Box 3)
  - Columbia Seminar, 1985 -- 1987; MS027.002.003.00029 (Box 3)
  - Conf. on Human Rights, 1967; MS027.002.004.00001 (Box 4)
  - Conscription Conference, 1989 -- 1990; MS027.002.004.00002 (Box 4)
  - Court of Man, 1969 -- 1977; MS027.002.004.00003 (Box 4)
  - CPPP - U.Md, 1976 -- 1984; MS027.002.004.00004 (Box 4)
  - Germany, 1988; MS027.002.004.00005 (Box 4)
  - Hastings Center, 1974; MS027.002.004.00006 (Box 4)
  - HAB - Vitae - Current, 1966 -- 1992; MS027.002.004.00007 (Box 4)
  - Iceland, 1998; MS027.002.004.00008 (Box 4)
  - ISISC Conference, 1987; MS027.002.004.00009 (Box 4)
  - Israel, 1988; MS027.002.004.00010 (Box 4)
  - ISSA Amsterdam, 1998; MS027.002.004.00011 (Box 4)
  - Just Deserts Conference, 1978; MS027.002.004.00012 (Box 4)
  - Kohlberg Conference, 1975; MS027.002.004.00013 (Box 4)
  - Madrid Conference, 1973; MS027.002.004.00014 (Box 4)
  - M. L. King Institute, 1970 -- 1979; MS027.002.004.00015 (Box 4)
    Contains letter from Coretta Scott King
    King, Coretta Scott
  - NEH Grant 1977 "Social Justice", MS027.002.004.00016 (Box 4)
  - NEH Proposal for Lawyer's Seminar, 1976; MS027.002.004.00017 (Box 4)
  - NEH Seminar Materials, 1975; MS027.002.004.00018 (Box 4)
  - Oregon, 1982; MS027.002.004.00019 (Box 4)
  - Originally Unlabeled Materials; Re: Amensty International, Coalition to Abolish the Death Penalty and Other Subjects (1 of 3), 1978 -- 1987; MS027.002.004.00020 (Box 4)
  - Originally Unlabeled Materials, Re: Amnesty International, Coalition to Abolish the Death Penalty and other Subjects (2 of 3), 1987; MS027.002.004.00021 (Box 4)
  - Originally unlabeled materials, Re: Amnesty International, Coalition to Abolish the Death Penalty and Other Subjects (3 of 3), 1987; MS027.002.004.00022 (Box 4)
  - Oxbridge, 1979 -- 1980; MS027.002.004.00023 (Box 4)
  - Oxford, 1988; MS027.002.004.00024 (Box 4)
  - Pardon, 1993; MS027.002.004.00025 (Box 4)
  - Pegasus, 1968 -- 1970; MS027.002.004.00026 (Box 4)
  - Phil. Dept. - General, 1968 -- 1987; MS027.002.004.00027 (Box 4)
  - Plattsburgh Conference, 1972 -- 1976; MS027.002.004.00028 (Box 4)
  - Prof. Hugo Bedau, Working Group on Human Rights and Security Assistance, 1977 -- 1978; MS027.002.004.00029 (Box 4)
  - Rawls - APA, 1977; MS027.002.004.00030 (Box 4)
  - Ripon Conference, 1970; MS027.002.004.00031 (Box 4)
  - Rockford College, 1973 -- 1974; MS027.002.004.00032 (Box 4)
  - Rutgers L.S. "Punishment", 1972; MS027.002.004.00033 (Box 4)
  - Sabbatical, 1994; MS027.002.004.00034 (Box 4)
  - Social Justice at Northwestern, 1976; MS027.002.004.00035 (Box 4)
  - Society for Philosophy and Public Affairs (1 of 2), 1975 -- 1982; MS027.002.005.00001 (Box 5)
  - Society for Philosophy and Public Affairs (2 of 2), 1969 -- 1971; MS027.002.005.00002 (Box 5)
  - South Africa Trip, 1981; MS027.002.005.00003 (Box 5)
  - SPPA, Ex. Com., 1972 -- 1973; MS027.002.005.00004 (Box 5)
  - Stockholm Trip, 1977; MS027.002.005.00005 (Box 5)
  - Talloires, 1996 -- 1998; MS027.002.005.00006 (Box 5)
  - Talloires, 1985; MS027.002.005.00007 (Box 5)
  - Talloires, 1991; MS027.002.005.00008 (Box 5)
  - Talloires, 1994; MS027.002.005.00009 (Box 5)
  - Thyssen C.P. Paper, 1977; MS027.002.005.00010 (Box 5)
  - Tufts Loyalty Oath, 1963 -- 1972; MS027.002.005.00011 (Box 5)
  - Tuskegee Racism Conference, 1973; MS027.002.005.00012 (Box 5)
  - Wayne L. Rev., 1987; MS027.002.005.00013 (Box 5)
  - Westminster, 1993 -- 1994; MS027.002.005.00014 (Box 5)
  - Yugoslavia, 1988; MS027.002.005.00015 (Box 5)
  - [Mixed Subject File #1], 1970 -- 1992; MS027.002.005.00016 (Box 5)
  - [Mixed Subject File #2], 1968 -- 1974; MS027.002.005.00017 (Box 5)
  - [Mixed Subject File #3], 1969 -- 1995; MS027.002.005.00018 (Box 5)
  - [Mixed Subject File #4], 1976 -- 1983; MS027.002.005.00019 (Box 5)
  - [Mixed Subject File #5], 1965 -- 1984; MS027.002.005.00020 (Box 5)
  - [Mixed Subject File #6], 1971 -- 1999; MS027.002.005.00021 (Box 5)
  - [Mixed Subject File #7], 1994 -- 1998; MS027.002.005.00022 (Box 5)
- Writings and Publications, 1949 -- 2001; MS027.003; 4.8 Linear Feet
  This series contains Bedau's files regarding articles, chapters and books he authored or reviewed. Files contain a mixture of drafts, related correspondence and publisher agreements. Also included are Bedau's Honors, Masters and Doctoral Theses.
  The bulk of these files are arranged alphabetically by publication title.
  - 25 Years at Harvard, 1996; MS027.003.006.00001 (Box 6)
  - Albion Talk, 1982; MS027.003.006.00002 (Box 6)
  - Anarchism Review, 1981; MS027.003.006.00003 (Box 6)
  - Are there crimes without victims?, 1974 -- 1989; MS027.003.006.00004 (Box 6)
  - Austin's Writings, 1963 -- 1964; MS027.003.006.00005 (Box 6)
  - Barry Review, 1973 -- 1975; MS027.003.006.00006 (Box 6)
  - Bedau / Schur Book (1 of 2), 1973 -- 1986; MS027.003.006.00007 (Box 6)
  - Bedau / Schur Books (2 of 2), 1973 -- 1986; MS027.003.006.00008 (Box 6)
  - Bedford Books Project, 1985 -- 1989; MS027.003.006.00009 (Box 6)
  - Behavior Med, 1974 -- 1983; MS027.003.006.00010 (Box 6)
  - Benditt, Rights, 1982; MS027.003.006.00011 (Box 6)
  - The Black Manifesto, 1972; MS027.003.006.00012 (Box 6)
  - C.D. and Health Care, 1991 -- 1993; MS027.003.006.00013 (Box 6)
  - C. D.and Personal Responsibility for Injustices, 1970; MS027.003.006.00014 (Box 6)
  - CD Bibliography, 1970; MS027.003.006.00015 (Box 6)
  - Civil Disobedience, 1993 -- 1994; MS027.003.006.00016 (Box 6)
  - Civil Disobedience (1 of 2), 1968 -- 1992; MS027.003.006.00017 (Box 6)
  - Civil Disobedience (2 of 2), 1967 -- 1970; MS027.003.006.00018 (Box 6)
  - Civility and Disobedience Review, 1975; MS027.003.006.00019 (Box 6)
  - Classification, 1981 -- 1984; MS027.003.006.00020 (Box 6)
  - Cohen C.D. review, 1971; MS027.003.006.00021 (Box 6)
  - Compensatory Justice, 1973 -- 1974; MS027.003.006.00022 (Box 6)
  - Complementarity, 1961 -- 1973; MS027.003.006.00023 (Box 6)
  - Complementarity in S / R, 1969 -- 1975; MS027.003.006.00024 (Box 6)
  - Cruel and Unusual Punishment Review, 1976 -- 1978; MS027.003.006.00025 (Box 6)
  - Democracy review, 1971 -- 1973; MS027.003.006.00026 (Box 6)
  - Divestment, 1989; MS027.003.006.00027 (Box 6)
  - Draft Registration, 1983; MS027.003.006.00028 (Box 6)
  - Ency. Applied Ethics, 1996; MS027.003.006.00029 (Box 6)
  - Ency. Crim. articles, 1994; MS027.003.006.00030 (Box 6)
  - Ency. War and Peace, 1993 -- 1994; MS027.003.007.00001 (Box 7)
  - Encyclopedia of Ethics, 1988 -- 1991; MS027.003.007.00002 (Box 7)
  - Environmental D.M., 1990 -- 1992; MS027.003.007.00003 (Box 7)
  - Equality, 1967; MS027.003.007.00004 (Box 7)
  - Ethical Decision Making, 1986; MS027.003.007.00005 (Box 7)
  - Ethical Decision Making, 1978 -- 1979; MS027.003.007.00006 (Box 7)
  - Excuses / Justification and T.V. violence, 1977 -- 1989; MS027.003.007.00007 (Box 7)
  - Genocide - Bulr Version, 1973 -- 1981; MS027.003.007.00008 (Box 7)
  - Genocide - World View Version, 1973 -- 1974; MS027.003.007.00009 (Box 7)
  - Genocide - SPPA Version, 1974 -- 1977; MS027.003.007.00010 (Box 7)
  - Genocide in Vietnam, 1972 -- 1983; MS027.003.007.00011 (Box 7)
  - Government Responsibility, 1979 -- 1985; MS027.003.007.00012 (Box 7)
  - Greenawalt Review, 1994; MS027.003.007.00013 (Box 7)
  - Group DM mss, 1982 -- 1983; MS027.003.007.00014 (Box 7)
  - Hardin Review, 1992 -- 1993; MS027.003.007.00015 (Box 7)
  - Hart's Conception of Law, 1963 -- 1964; MS027.003.007.00016 (Box 7)
  - Human Rights, 1982 -- 1983; MS027.003.007.00017 (Box 7)
  - Human Rights book review, 1971 -- 1973; MS027.003.007.00018 (Box 7)
  - Human Rights and Foreign Policy, 1977 -- 1980; MS027.003.007.00019 (Box 7)
  - Inequality, Hiram CoH. Penn. State, 1973 -- 1981; MS027.003.007.00020 (Box 7)
  - International Human Rights, 1981 -- 1982; MS027.003.008.00001 (Box 8)
  - Juris Doctor Review, 1972; MS027.003.008.00002 (Box 8)
  - Justice and Equality MSS, 1968 -- 1996; MS027.003.008.00003 (Box 8)
  - Justice and Utility, 1963 -- 1968; MS027.003.008.00004 (Box 8)
  - Kaufman review, 1990 -- 1991; MS027.003.008.00005 (Box 8)
  - Law and Justice: Nation Review, 1963; MS027.003.008.00006 (Box 8)
  - Law and Natural Law: Nation Review, 1965; MS027.003.008.00007 (Box 8)
  - Law and Society - May '74, 1974 -- 1975; MS027.003.008.00008 (Box 8)
  - Liberal Democracy, 1980 -- 1981; MS027.003.008.00009 (Box 8)
  - "Limits of the Law's Effectiveness", 1971 -- 1972; MS027.003.008.00010 (Box 8)
  - McPherson review, 1975; MS027.003.008.00011 (Box 8)
  - Midwest Studies Paper, 1976 -- 1979; MS027.003.008.00012 (Box 8)
  - Military Obligation, 1972 -- 1983; MS027.003.008.00013 (Box 8)
  - Nation C.D. review, 1971; MS027.003.008.00014 (Box 8)
  - Oberlin Colloquium, 1971; MS027.003.008.00015 (Box 8)
  - Originally Unlabeled Materials, RE Civil Disobedience in Focus (1 of 2), 1990 -- 1997; MS027.003.008.00016 (Box 8)
  - Originally Unlabeled Materials; RE Civil Disobedience in Focus (2 of 2), 1989; MS027.003.008.00017 (Box 8)
  - Originally Unlabeled Folder, RE Human Rights, 1977; MS027.003.008.00018 (Box 8)
  - Originally Unlabeled Materials, RE: Law and Objectivity, 1994; MS027.003.008.00019 (Box 8)
  - Originally Unlabeled Materials, RE: Making Moral Choices, 1995 -- 1997; MS027.003.008.00020 (Box 8)
  - Originally Unlabeled Materials, RE: Making Mortal Choices, Tragic Choice and Jim in the Jungle, 1993 -- 1996; MS027.003.008.00021 (Box 8)
  - Originally Unlabeled Materials, RE: Multiple Articles, 1992 -- 1996; MS027.003.008.00022 (Box 8)
  - Originally Unlabeled Materials, RE: On Human Rights, 1994; MS027.003.008.00023 (Box 8)
  - Originally Unlabeled Materials, RE: Tragic Choices Lectures, 1995; MS027.003.008.00024 (Box 8)
  - Oxford C. to Phil., 1992 -- 1994; MS027.003.008.00025 (Box 8)
  - Oxford Companion to the S.C., 1989 -- 1991; MS027.003.008.00026 (Box 8)
  - Philosophy Forum, 1968 -- 1969; MS027.003.008.00027 (Box 8)
  - Precarious Sovereignty, 1997 -- 1998; MS027.003.008.00028 (Box 8)
  - Prisoners' RTS, 1981 -- 1985; MS027.003.009.00001 (Box 9)
  - Production of Making Decisions, 1978 -- 1981; MS027.003.009.00002 (Box 9)
  - "Purloined Prose", 1991; MS027.003.009.00003 (Box 9)
  - Quality of Life, 1979 -- 1984; MS027.003.009.00004 (Box 9)
  - Rakowski Review, 1982; MS027.003.009.00005 (Box 9)
  - Retribution in Omaha, 1976 -- 1980; MS027.003.009.00006 (Box 9)
  - Review of Donnelly, 1989 -- 1991; MS027.003.009.00007 (Box 9)
  - Review of Hudson, 1988; MS027.003.009.00008 (Box 9)
  - Review of Rawls, Justice, 1972; MS027.003.009.00009 (Box 9)
  - Review of Richards, Sex, etc, 1982 -- 1983; MS027.003.009.00010 (Box 9)
  - Review of Ten, 1990 -- 1991; MS027.003.009.00011 (Box 9)
  - Review of Ten, 1989; MS027.003.009.00012 (Box 9)
  - Revolution, 1971; MS027.003.009.00013 (Box 9)
  - Revolution in Cleveland, 1975 -- 1976; MS027.003.009.00014 (Box 9)
  - Right to Life, 1967; MS027.003.009.00015 (Box 9)
  - Right to Life review, 1985 -- 1989; MS027.003.009.00016 (Box 9)
  - Rights as Claims etc, 1968 -- 1977; MS027.003.009.00017 (Box 9)
  - Schabas review, 1994; MS027.003.009.00018 (Box 9)
  - Sen Review, 1992; MS027.003.009.00019 (Box 9)
  - Skinner Review, 1971 -- 1972; MS027.003.009.00020 (Box 9)
  - Social Justice, 1982; MS027.003.009.00021 (Box 9)
  - Social Justice and Equality, 1976; MS027.003.009.00022 (Box 9)
  - Social Justice and Quality of Life, 1976; MS027.003.009.00023 (Box 9)
  - Summers Review, 1972 -- 1973; MS027.003.009.00024 (Box 9)
  - Thomson Review, 1992; MS027.003.009.00025 (Box 9)
  - Tribe review, 1991; MS027.003.009.00026 (Box 9)
  - Utilitarianism Review, 1984 -- 1985; MS027.003.009.00027 (Box 9)
  - Vaux Review, 1993; MS027.003.009.00028 (Box 9)
  - Wilson, Equality (review), 1967 -- 1968; MS027.003.009.00029 (Box 9)
  - World without Punishment, 1975; MS027.003.009.00030 (Box 9)
  - Zashin Review, 1972; MS027.003.009.00031 (Box 9)
  - [Miscellaneous Writings and Publications], 1963 -- 2001; MS027.003.009.00032 (Box 9)
  - [Miscellaneous Writings and Publications], 1997 -- 1999; MS027.003.009.00033 (Box 9)
  - Tisch Library Pamphlet File, 1961 -- 1965; MS027.003.009.00034 (Box 9)
  - Honors Thesis Volume II: Background and Trends of Spanish-American Philosophy in South America from the Sixteenth to the Twentieth Centuries, 1949; MS027.003.009.00035 (Box 9)
  - Master's Thesis: Philosophical Doctrines in Tertulluaan's De Anima, 1951; MS027.003.009.00036 (Box 9)
  - Doctoral Thesis: Concept of Thinking, 1961; MS027.003.009.00037 (Box 9)